<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section>
  <title>Pending Website Feature Enhancements and Bug Fixes </title>

  <para>This needs some more feature enhancement and bug fixes. If you have
  interested in helping out please contact me. Expecially useful would be
  persons with experience with <ulink
  url="www.wordpress.org">Wordpress</ulink>. Here is a list of current issues
  which need help/improvement.</para>

  <section>
    <title>Permalinks</title>

    <para>Given a permalink with the name
    http://www.blincubator.com/bi_library/safe-numerics I expect to be able to
    jump directly to the library page for the safe-numerics library. I would
    like to be able to fix this but so far I have been unable to do so.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Library Statistics</title>

    <para>Right now we you SlimStat to gather and monitor statistics on each
    library as well as the web site as a whole. It's a great package and has
    served us very well. Still there a few issues which I would like to see
    resolved.<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>users can only see the slimstat statistics pages if they are
          logged in to the site. I would like to eliminate this requirement
          but haven't been able to figure out how to do this.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>On the page for each library I'd like to gather and display
          the following<itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>number of times the repo link has been invoked</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>number of times the download link has been
                invoked</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>number of times the documentation link has been
                invoked</para>
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>I'd like to get a list of all the users who downloaded and/or
          followed the link to the library repo. I want to do this so I can
          email them a reminder to review and/or comment on the library after
          they've had a chance to evaluate it.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
  </section>
</section>
