<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
  <section>
    <title>Keep Notes as You Make Changes</title>

    <para>Many libraries have a section entitled "Rationale". This section is
    very helpful for anyone who want's to use the library. The problem is that
    if you wait until you're done to write this section, you can't remember
    what the key decisions were and why you made them. That is, you don't
    remember all the dead ends you discarded to get your final finished
    product. If your library gets to review, someone will suggest that it you
    should of done it using method X instead of method Y</para>

    <para>"Easy" way - don't keep notes. Here's what happens.</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>At some point in the development, you discover that you want to
        change a design decision. This means you have to use method X instead
        of method Y. Generally this will occur more than once during the
        development.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Finally you get everything done, and submit your library for
        review.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Now some smart guy will make a good case for using method Y
        instead of method X which you used. Of course you know that since
        you've been down that road. But now you don't remember exactly why
        method Y couldn't be made to work.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>So you sort of fake it with a glib response which only provokes
        your critic to make an even stronger case. Now everything has
        escalated to the point where you have to go back and make a really
        exahaustive explanation (maybe even involving sample code!). This
        sucks up a huge amount of time.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>"Hard" way - keep notes on your decisions as you go:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>When you discover you want to change a design decision, add an
        explanation to your log.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Keeping such notes diminishes the possibility that you
        accidently change a design decision back to one that has previously
        been determined to be a dead end. Don't laugh - this is not hard to
        do!</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>When writing documentation, take these notes, clean them up and
        include them in a section called "Rationale". This makes writing this
        very useful documentation trivial.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Users and library reviewers will be able to see your case before
        they make their "suggestions". This short circuits lot's of pointless
        discussions. There will likely still be differences of opinion, but
        all the issues will be visible to all parties at the same time.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
