<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="introduction">
  <title>Introduction</title>

  <para>The goal of this web site is to help C++ programmers produce C++ code
  libraries as good as those libraries accepted into <ulink
  url="http://www.boost.org">Boost</ulink></para>

  <para>Most of the information contained here is my personal view which has
  been shaped by my experience as developer of the <ulink
  url="http://www.boost.org/doc/libs/1_50_0/libs/serialization/doc/index.html">Boost
  Serialization Library</ulink>.</para>

  <note>
    <para><emphasis>In no way should any information found on these pages be
    construed as reflecting any "official" policy or recommendation of <ulink
    url="http://www.boost.org">Boost</ulink></emphasis>.</para>
  </note>

  <section>
    <title>Observations and Premises</title>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>The Boost review is the essence of boost.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>There aren't really enough reviews for many packages.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Many libraries really aren't ready for review.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>When the review comes up, there's a two week period and everyone
        who wants to participate has to adjust to this period. I'm sure lots
        of people don't participate because of scheduling issues.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Writing a library is very difficult and an immense amount of
        work. This diminishes the number of libraries submitted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para><ulink url="http://www.boost.org">Boost</ulink> has largely
    fulfilled it's original mission of supplying necessary components to the
    C++ standard libary. But there is much more to be done! In order to
    continue to succeed, C++ needs more and better libraries. This web site is
    intended promote them!</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Work Flow</title>

    <para>Library authors prepare their submissions in accordance with the
    guidelines set by this web site and upload their submission. The
    submission is subjected to a pre-review to verify that it meets minimum
    standards for consideration to be part of Boost. These standards
    include:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Directory structure</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Documentation and completeness</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Testing</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Portability</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Licensing</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Availability</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>Note that this pre-review doesn't address subjective aspects such as
    the quality of the submission, usefulness, etc. It only addresses those
    things that can be verified by following a checklist. The submission is
    made available for download and a project page is opened for this
    submission. This project page will be used to keep a record of information
    regarding the submission as it becomes available. This information will
    include:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Reports of bugs</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Requests for features</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Reviews</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>User ratings</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Download statistics</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Testing results</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Observations on design and implementation</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Any other useful and relevant information</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>User ratings</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>Library users are encouraged to participate the process by
    installing, testing, commenting on and reviewing libaries which interest
    them. Others are encouraged promote library development by sponsoring
    libraries which they find useful.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Desired Outcome</title>

    <section>
      <title>Improved review process</title>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>More people will have downloaded and tested the submission and
          will have provided feedback and reviews on the library's "issues"
          page.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>For some libraries, "issues" history will make it obvious that
          the library would not pass the formal review process. The whole
          review process can be skipped in this case.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>For some libraries, the "issues" history will make it clear
          that acceptance is a "no-brainer". The review process will be much
          simpler in this case.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Everyone who has an interest will be able to contribute to the
          review process even if they can't commit to a specific time/date
          window.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>The review manager will have a wealth of information available
          that he doesn't have now. This will make the process much easier
          than it is now.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Easier library development</title>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Authors can get feedback before the submission is reviewed
          while there is still an opportunity to make adjustments.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Libraries can start small and have features added
          incrementally until they are ready for review.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>A library feature set can be developed in accordance with
          experience of real users. This should make the library more likely
          to get a better review and diminish the amount of effort expended on
          features for which there is little demand.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>User feedback may motivate authors to spend more effort
          finishing the library.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Test results from a variety of platforms will be available to
          help authors make their library portable.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>More support for library authors</title>

      <para>Interested parties will be ecouraged to provide financial and
      logistical support to authors of libraries which they find useful to
      their organizational goals. This will permit more people to participate
      in library development and hopefully result in a higher number of
      quality library submissions.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
</section>
