<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="introduction">
  <title>Library Sponsorship</title>

  <para>Software development is expensive. By spreading expense among many
  users, cost per user is reduced. This is what open source does. Open source
  software has these advantages</para>

  <para><itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inexpensive to acquire - often FREE.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Tested/Validated by many other people</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Better Documented</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Effectively amounts to free outsourcing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>On the other hand, there are some disadvantages.</para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Quality is uneven. Documentation may be weak, code may not be
      portable, and code might not be well tested</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>Support is often nil.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>Less than perfect match for the user's use case.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <para>Library sponsorship can help address some of the above disadvantages.
  Sponsors can arrange for library developers to:</para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>improve quality with better documentation, more tests, etc.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>add features and/or functionality which would otherwise be
      considered to specific</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>provide support related to the specific usage scenarios</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <para>So of open source software development amounts to "FREE" outsourcing,
  Sponsorship will amount to "inexpensive" outsourcing. You get what you pay
  for.</para>

  <para>In addition to the above, library sponsors can arrange to get their
  log and link placed on the library page. This might provide them with some
  other benefits:</para>

  <para>This might be very interesting to a wider audience. Sponsoring
  organizations might</para>

  <para><itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Demonstrate their commitment to high quality C++ software
        development. This is helpful for acquiring the most capable
        programmers.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Be looking for specific skill set. For example, organizations
        using Software Transactional Memory (STM) might want to display their
        logo on the library submission page which implements such a library.
        Programmers interested in the topic would be exposed to this logo
        which can be clicked through the organizations web page.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Be offering proprietary alternatives to the submitted library.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>Compensation of library authors is a private arrangement
  between the author and the sponsor. The Boost Library Incubator has no
  involvement in this negotiation and/or transaction. Sponsors might
  offer</para>

  <para><itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Payment for specific tasks such as library enhancements or
        support</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Payment for placing the sponsors logo/link on the library
        submission page.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>library authors employed by them to work on their library on
        company time and resources.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>reimbursement of expenses to go to C++ conferences</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>anything else.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>This concept of library sponsorship is an experimental
  attempt to address the main conundrum of open source software: The better it
  is, the less demand for improvement, fixes, enhancements, updates etc. and
  hence less potential revenue for the creator. Hopefully, this idea will
  create motivation library users to create incentives for library authors to
  make more and better C++ libraries.</para>
</section>
