<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="introduction">
  <title>Boost Library Writers Workshop</title>

  <para>Boost library Incubator is proud announce the Library Writers Workshop
  to be hosted as an <ulink url="http://cppcon.org/">Open Content session at
  CPP Con 2014</ulink> Monday, September 8 at 8:30 PM. The goal of this
  workshop is to help potential library authors acquire the tools, skills and
  motivation to develop a boost library candidate and submit it to the <ulink
  url="www.blincubator.com">Boost Library Incubator</ulink>. This is an
  opportunity for library authors to get feedback on their progress and
  encouragement for their efforts<emphasis>.</emphasis><note>
      <para><emphasis>One of the great things about this workshop is that you
      don't have to be registered for CPP Con to participate !!!</emphasis>
      You can just drop in and participate if you're in the area !!!. I'm
      hoping to see some interesting efforts. (Hmmm - what about remote
      participation?).</para>
    </note></para>

  <section>
    <title>Requirements</title>

    <para>There two types of attendees: Library Authors and Observers. The
    method used will be peer critique. In order to participate as an Observer,
    all one has to do is show up. In order to participate as an author, one
    must:</para>

    <para><itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Have a library in progress.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Have documentation and perhaps code which is accessible
          online.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Create a comment entry below which includes</para>

          <para><itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Name of the library</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Short description of what the library does</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Links to documentation and perhaps code</para>
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>

          <para>Create your entry as soon as you know you'll be attending the
          workshop as an author. This way we'll be able to save you a
          space.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Program</title>

    <para>The workshop will operate on the following schedule:</para>

    <para><itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>8:30 PM - 8:35 PM I will introduce the workshop with a short
          summary of these rules and answer any questions.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>8:35 PM - 9:00 PM Each library author will make a very short
          presentation (~3 min) of what his library attempts to
          accomplish.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>9:00 PM Authors draw lots to select a library other than their
          own. Observers are also permitted to draw lots or just select a
          library they might be interested in. Observers might choose to leave
          at this point.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>9:00 PM - 10:00 PM Each selected library is “critiqued” by
          reading through the documentation and perhaps code while building a
          contemporaneous log on the experience. This log will be posted as a
          comment below.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>10:00 PM - Pencils down - wrap up. Authors may read and
          optionally reply to critiques at their leisure.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>

    <para>I will be available to answer questions and provide encouragement.
    Hopefully I can convince another boost library author to attend</para>
  </section>
</section>
