<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="requirements_documentation">
  <title>Documentation</title>

  <para>Documentation of software libraries and APIs has a well deserved
  reputation for being obtuse, opaque, incomplete, hard to use and not very
  helpful. Boost documentation is better, but still not good enough. One of
  the main motivations of this website is to improve documentation of
  libraries submitted to Boost.</para>

  <section>
    <title>Structure</title>

    <para><emphasis>A library MUST contain a doc/html directory with an
    included file index.html. The documentation should be browsable with or
    without being connected to the net.</emphasis></para>

    <para>Optionally, it may include Information to build the HTML directory
    from other tools such DocBook, BoostBook or QuickBook or some other
    system. These systems provide the benefit of being able to generate output
    formats other than HTML such as PDF, ebook and others.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Contents</title>

    <para>What should documentation for a software library contain? The answer
    turns out to be surprisingly un obvious.</para>

    <para>The obvious thing seems to just write expanded information about
    each class and function. However, it's very difficult to keep this from
    ending up just paraphrasing the code. Documentation which is prepared
    separately is much more likely to manifest "conceptual integrity". That
    is, it is likely to look like a set of minimally coupled, composable
    orthogonal ideas whose purpose and usage is easy to understand. Generating
    or writing documentation from the completed code is more likely to result
    in a library that looks like a collection of dependent components which
    are harder to understand and use. For this reason, I advocate building the
    documentation concurrently with the code rather than waiting for the code
    to be written and tested.</para>

    <para>Documentation of types and functions is essential. But it doesn't
    address the documentation of template classes and functions. A template is
    a group of classes or functions rather than just one of these. So all the
    information which is fixed for a class or function such as arguments can't
    be specified.. This problem has been addressed by the adoption of concepts
    and concept checking classes. Just as function type signatures specify the
    types a <emphasis>function</emphasis> takes as arguments, concepts specify
    which types can be used as <emphasis>template</emphasis> arguments. The
    word <emphasis>concept </emphasis>is very confusing. A better term would
    be <emphasis>type requirements</emphasis> but <emphasis>concept</emphasis>
    is the historically accepted term so we'll continue to use it here. Here
    is more information helpful for writing documentation using
    concepts:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink
          url="http://www.sgi.com/tech/stl/doc_introduction.html">How to use
          the STL documentation</ulink> This the key document which describes
          how to write documentation for C++ library which might contain
          templates. The <ulink url="http://www.sgi.com/tech/stl/">STL
          website</ulink> is the original source for the STL library and hence
          contains of how the above description is used.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><ulink
          url="http://www.boost.org/doc/libs/1_51_0/libs/fusion/doc/html/">Fusion</ulink>
          I found this Boost library to be the single most helpful example of
          how to write good documentation.</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>It's a real example - not an explanation of how to do
              it</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>It's a very large library with many facets. But the
              documentation is very regular in that the same patterns
              described above are used throughout. Once you get how it works
              for one part of the library the rest of it very familiar. If you
              use <ulink
              url="http://www.boost.org/doc/libs/1_49_0/libs/fusion/doc/html/">Fusion</ulink>
              you'll spend hours (or days) pouring over this documentation.
              But you'll never feel that you're lost - just awed
              inspired.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="kempf.html">Writing Documentation for
          Boost</ulink></para>

          <para>This is what the boost website says about documentation. It
          seems well written, and it's not really inconsistent with the above,
          but by itself, it wasn't enough for me to get me on the right
          track.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>

    <para>I've attempted to synthesize information from the above sources into
    the following "templates" which a library author can "fill in". One can
    include these templates in his library documentation, eliminate those
    section which are not applicable, and fill in the information particular
    to his component.</para>

    <para>Here is an <link linkend="library">outline</link> of what library
    documentation should look like. Not all libraries need all the sections,
    but most should be there. Links point to "mock ups" for the corresponding
    section which can be used as a basis of creating your own
    documentation.</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Introduction</para>

        <para>A concise description of what the library does. The object is to
        give the reader enough information to know whether this library
        addresses the need which lead him to check this documentation in the
        first place. Often times, a short motivating example can show what
        "problem" the library solves and how it is used to do it.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Tutorial</para>

        <para>Detailed examples of library usage. These examples should
        include code that the user can build and try on his own.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Notes</para>

        <para>Include useful formation which doesn't fit anywhere else.
        Examples would be:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Pointers to other libraries which do a similar thing.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Information on testing.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>compiler/platform quirks and dependencies.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><link linkend="concept">Concepts</link></para>

        <para>List of concepts defined by the library.</para>

        <para>Each concept is a description of a set of operations that a type
        must support in order to be considered as meeting the requirements of
        the concept. The concept name is a succinct way of specifying the
        constraints on type parameters passed to C++ templates. Note that you
        need document only the new concepts you create. Those that are
        included from the Boost Concept Check headers are already
        documented.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><link linkend="type">Types</link></para>

        <para>List of C++ types defined by the library.</para>

        <para>A type used by the library. A type may be a C++ template, class
        or structure. If it is a template, there are no type parameters so
        that section can be dropped. If its a class, member functions will be
        documented in the section "New Valid Expressions". This is somewhat
        different than the traditional way of documenting class member
        functions and types. The advantage is that is more compatible with the
        documentation of template types. In any case, the actual class header
        is available for reference.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><link linkend="function">Functions</link></para>

        <para>List of non-member functions and function templates.</para>

        <para>C++ functions and function templates can be documented the same
        way. The only difference is that for functions, the type requirement
        section can be deleted.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Rationale</para>

        <para>While working on your library, keep a list of reasons for the
        design decisions you made. Include that list here.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Change Log</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Acknowledgements</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>References</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>Note the strong similarity in the documentation for <ulink
    url="concept.html">Concept</ulink> and <ulink
    url="type.html">Type</ulink>.</para>

    <para>The above Outline for a simple library with a smaller number of
    concepts, types and functions. For a example where the number is much
    larger you can check <ulink
    url="http://www.boost.org/doc/libs/1_49_0/libs/fusion/doc/html/">Fusion</ulink>.
    This library ls really a group of smaller libraries each with it's own set
    of concepts, types and functions.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>References</title>

    <para>The information in this section is meant to be consistent with
    generally accepted standards and recommendations for C++14. For more
    information see <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink
          url="http://www.sgi.com/tech/stl/doc_introduction.html">How to use
          the STL documentation</ulink></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><ulink
          url="https://isocpp.org/files/papers/N3797.pdf">N3797</ulink> C++14
          standard section 17.5 Method of description (Informative)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
  </section>
</section>
