<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section>
  <title>Deployment</title>

  <para>Filling the form in the <ulink url="???">Library Submission
  Page</ulink> fulfills the requirements for deployment of a library. When the
  form is submitted, it is checked by a human to verify that all the
  information is properly filled in and that the submission fulfils all the
  requirements of this website.</para>

  <para>The form contains links to where the required facilities such as
  reviews, documentation, download, code repository, and issue tracking. That
  is, this website does not implement all the facilities required. For
  example, we require an issue tracking system, but don't implement one here.
  Even if we do provide such an implementation in the future, library
  submissions will not be required to use it. This policy/design provides a
  number of benefits:<itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Library authors can use their preferred set of resources. In
        many cases, library authors have these things already set up there is
        nothing to do but to link to them.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Libraries differ greatly in their requirements. A very small
        header library may not need a full featured/elaborate revision
        tracking system while a larger complex library might require such a
        system. This model permits each library to choose the best set of
        resources.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>As time passes, better facilities become available. If a library
        author wants to migrate his revision control system from one to
        another he can do that without having to get permission from some
        higher coordinating authority.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Library modularization is encouraged. Users will download the
        libraries which interest them - not necessarily some whole set. For a
        library to be successful, it will have to minimize unnecessary
        coupling to other libraries. This is a good thing.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>We expect users who download libraries on this site to run the
        regression/acceptance tests on their local platform and report their
        results to a central site. This distributes testing among users in way
        that will always scale.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist></para>

  <para>This deployment model contrasts starkly with that of Boost itself.
  Boost is distinguished by</para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>The libraries are distributed all at once in one large zip file or
      tarball. Once one downloads and installs this package, he has all he
      boost libraries available. Any decision to change the composition of
      this package - e.g. Deprecation of a library, is arrived at by consensus
      of boost developers. Since testing occurs every day on the whole
      distribution, users can be confident that everything will work even if
      libraries have been coupled together - inadvertently or
      otherwise.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>libraries don't have their own version numbers. Version numbers
      are assigned to each boost distribution. Note that the recent Boost
      modularization requires per library version numbers, but this
      requirement is not yet enforced.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>All libraries use the same system for code repositories, reviews,
      issue tracking and the like. Any change in the selection of these
      facilities can only occur by reaching a consensus of boost
      developers.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>Test are run on all the whole boost distribution every day. The
      system works amazingly well. But it takes quite a bit of resources at
      the testing sites.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <section>
    <title>Links</title>

    <para>The <link linkend="submit-my-library">Library Submission Page</link>
    contains links to point to implementations of required facilities.</para>

    <informaltable>
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <colspec align="left"/>

        <colspec align="left" colwidth="3*"/>

        <thead>
          <row>
            <entry align="left">Link</entry>

            <entry align="left">Function</entry>
          </row>
        </thead>

        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry>Reviews</entry>

            <entry>link to browseable online library HTML
            documentation</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Documentation</entry>

            <entry>link to browse able online library HTML
            documentation</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Download</entry>

            <entry>link to a page from which the library can downloaded.
            Typically such a page would offer one or more common formats such
            as ZIP and/or Tarball files.</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Code Repository</entry>

            <entry>link to a source code repository. This code repository
            should include the whole project directory structure.</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>Issues</entry>

            <entry>link to a page where users can post problems and they can
            be discussed with the library author.</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </informaltable>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Options</title>

    <para>There are <ulink
    url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_open_source_software_hosting_facilities">multitudes
    of online services</ulink> for hosting a library. I've spent some time
    investigating some of the more popular one. They all provide some of the
    services described above - but none of them provides them all. Of course
    there is no reason that a library has to depend on only one of these
    services. One can just as well register his library on more than one
    service and use the <link linkend="submit-my-library">Library Submission
    Page</link> as a gateway to the various facilities used.</para>

    <para>Here is my short assessment of some of the more popular services.
    For illustrative purposes we've used the safe numerics library to show how
    links should be filled for on each service on our <link
    linkend="submit-my-library">Library Submission Page</link> .</para>

    <section>
      <title>Google Code</title>

      <para><itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Reviews - not supported. It does have a configurable Wiki
            which could be "made to work", but this option would be more
            effort that it's probably worth.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Documentation - No special facilities for reading HTML
            documentation prepared in accordance with our requirements. Using
            the configurable Wiki would require hand converting to the Wiki
            format - not a practical option.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Code repository - supports Git, Subversion and Mercurial. -
            an example of a link to browse code would be <ulink
            url="http://code.google.com/p/safe-numerics/source">http://code.google.com/p/safe-numerics/source</ulink></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Download - project download supports any files you upload.
            The link for this page would be <ulink
            url="http://code.google.com/p/safe-numerics/downloads/list">http://code.google.com/p/safe-numerics/downloads/list</ulink></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Issues - has a serviceable issue tracking page which can be
            accessed by <ulink
            url="http://code.google.com/p/safe-numerics/issues/list">http://code.google.com/p/safe-numerics/issues/list</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>Google Code doesn't have all we want/need but it may be
      worth using in some circumstances.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>SourceForge.net</title>

      <para><itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Reviews - has the ability to create a custom forum. This
            looks like a good match for the reviews we want our library to
            accumulate. Link to <ulink
            url="https://sourceforge.net/p/safenumerics/discussion/">https://sourceforge.net/p/safenumerics/discussion/</ulink></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Documentation - No special facilities. SourceForge.net does
            include the facility "project page" which could be made to work to
            hold the documentation. And I have seen for some projects, but I
            couldn't get it to configured despite a sincere effort and some
            communication with tech support.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Code repository - supports SVN, Git and Mercurial. For Git,
            the link would be: <ulink
            url="https://sourceforge.net/p/safenumerics/code/ci/master/tree/">https://sourceforge.net/p/safenumerics/code/ci/master/tree/</ulink></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Download - you upload deployment packages "by hand". The
            link to the "files" <ulink
            url="https://sourceforge.net/projects/safenumerics/files/">https://sourceforge.net/projects/safenumerics/files/</ulink></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Issues - <ulink
            url="https://sourceforge.net/p/safenumerics/tickets/">https://sourceforge.net/p/safenumerics/tickets/</ulink></para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>GitHub</title>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Reviews - not supported. Git does have a facility named "code
          review" but it's not the same as what we've called "formal review".
          Git also has a Wiki which might be made to work - but it's a little
          bit crude for our purposes.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Documentation - Includes the facility to browse HTML files in
          the project via any java script compatible browser. Since libraries
          on this site are required to provide browsable documentation in
          HTML, this is an incredibly convenient facility. The only thing we
          have to do is specify the correct link on our <link
          linkend="submit-my-library">Library Submission Page</link> . The
          Using safe_numerics library as an example, the link would be:</para>

          <para><ulink
          url="http://htmlpreview.github.com/?https://raw.github.com/robertramey/safe_numerics/master/safe_numerics/doc/html/index.html">http://htmlpreview.github.com/?https://raw.github.com/robertramey/safe_numerics/master/safe_numerics/doc/html/index.html</ulink></para>

          <para>Now we don't have to find a separate place to load our
          documentation so that potential users may review the documentation
          prior to downloading the library. Whenever we push our local copy to
          the repository, the documentation is automatically synchronized with
          the code.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Code repository - Uses Git (naturally)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Download - Includes a download facility for any project
          loaded. The correct link would be <ulink
          url="https://github.com/robertramey/safe_numerics/archive/master.zip">https://github.com/robertramey/safe_numerics/archive/master.zip</ulink></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Issues - Includes a simple Issues facility automatically for
          any project loaded. The correct link to paste into the <link
          linkend="submit-my-library">Library Submission Page</link> would be
          <ulink
          url="https://github.com/robertramey/safe_numerics/issues">https://github.com/robertramey/safe_numerics/issues</ulink></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>All in all, GitHub is <emphasis>almost</emphasis> a perfect match
      for our purposes. In addition, Boost itself has
      <emphasis>modularized</emphasis> it's libraries and each one has it's
      own separate repository on GitHub. Experience with this has been very
      positive. Given all this, GitHub would have to be the preferred choice
      unless there are some very compelling reasons to choose something
      else.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
</section>
